Sean Haines

seanhaines13@gmail.com

Github • LinkedIn • Portfolio

Overview

I consider myself a fully stacked Front-End developer with a deep passion for design, user experience and interface. I have the ability to develop web applications from concept to implementation with experience in user research, testing and development. My professional goals are to continuously add new tools of the trade to my utility belt while working with an amazing and driven team.

Education

Full Stack Web Development, 2015 Coding Dojo, Bellevue, Washington

Bachelor of Arts in Community Health Education, 2008

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

Professional Experience

Web Developer, Sept. 2015 – *Present* Mentor Ventures, Inc., Kirkland, Washington

Working alongside of the Chief designer, I am responsible for all web and mobile app landing page development.

UI Developer, Aug. 2015 – *Present* Avanade, Seattle, Washington

I was brought on a short-term contract to assist in the ExxonMobil Fuel & Lubes Division to implement and develop new front-end resources and components utilizing SCSS, and Angular.

Web Developer, May 2015 – *Present* Freelance Web Designer & Developer

Team Lead, Mar. 2013 – Feb. 2015

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

Led team meetings to discuss daily tasks and monthly goals to ensure high levels of efficiency and customer service within the organization. Assisted with the screening, hiring and training of new staff while managing the day-to-day operations of the case management team. Coordinated new strategies and process improvements. Compiled monthly, quarterly and annual reports showing the success and growth of all programs. Developed training materials.

Case Manager II, May 2010 – Feb. 2013 Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

Restructured dental program's processes, which increased client referral numbers by 1,200% over 2 years. Scheduled high volumes of medical and dental appointments across multiple counties for uninsured and Medicaid clients. Daily data entry of incoming referrals, medical chart notes, enrollment applications, and clinical records requests.

Eligibility and Enrollment Specialist, Jun. 2008 – Apr. 2010 Coalition of Community Health Clinics, Portland, Oregon

Technical Toolbox

Languages HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, SASS/SCSS, JADE

Libraries & Frameworks

Angular.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, CodeIgniter, Express.js, Socket.io, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose.js

Databases

Mongodb, MySQL

Servers

Apache, Node.js

Tools

Gulp.js, Sublime Text, Atom Text Editor, Visual Studio, Git/Github, Terminal/Command Line

Methodology MVC, OOP, RESTful

